[{"front":"Which of the following statements are true of OpenUI5?","options":{"A":"OpenUI5 includes all the main features of SAPUI5","B":"OpenUI5 contains sap.viz and sap.ui.comp","C":"OpenUI5 is free for use","D":"OpenUI5 implements its own Core-Component","E":"OpenUI5 encompasses the complete SAPUI5 Core, plus many front-end controls that are also included with SAPUI5"},"back":["A","C","E"]},{"front":"What annotation is used to define the heading of list report?","back":"@UI.headerInfo.typeNamePlural"},{"front":"Which areas were re-imagined in SAP S/4HANA?","back":"User Experience, Business Processes, System Configuration, Database Models"},{"front":"What property is used in the manifest file, to configure how the selection and presentation variants display using a single variant managment area?","back":"smartVariantManagment"},{"front":"Which of the following lifecycle hook methods can be implemented by the developer in a view controller?","options":{"A":"onInit","B":"onRender","C":"onAfterRendering","D":"onExit","E":"onBeforeRendering"},"back":["A","C","D","E"]},{"front":"Which function is provided to register a URL prefix for a module name prefix?","back":"JQuery.sap.registerModulePath()"},{"front":"How many columns are supported by the flexible-column layout?","back":"3"},{"front":"Which of the following should you avoid with regard to the golden rule 'Every SAP Fiori app must run as a web app'","options":{"A":"Absolute URLs generated in front or back-end","B":"Using SAPUI5","C":"Hard dependencies between apps","D":"Calling UI2 services directly instead of using APIs","E":"Use of platform specific functionality without availability check"},"back":["A","C","D","E"]},{"front":"Which root element can be used when developing a worklist app?","back":"sap.m.App"},{"front":"What is needed to define a target mapping for an ABAP transaction?","back":"Transaction code, System alias"},{"front":"Which of the following templates display only one business entity?","options":{"A":"List Report","B":"Object Page","C":"Overview Page","D":"Analytic List Page"},"back":["B"]},{"front":"Which task lists for SAP Fiori are run only once per ABAP system release?","back":"SAP_FIORI_FOUNDATION_S4, SAP_GW_FIORI_ERP_ONE_CLNT_SETUP"},{"front":"Which of the following parameters must you provide when you create an initial cloud connector configuration?","options":{"A":"Region","B":"Display Name","C":"Subaccount","D":"Password","E":"Location ID","F":"Description"},"back":["A","C","D"]},{"front":"Which of the following types are types of cards in an overview page?","options":{"A":"List","B":"Link List","C":"Analytic","D":"Table","E":"Stack"},"back":["A","B","C","D","E"]},{"front":"What parameter is needed when instantiating a MockServer object?","back":"rootUri"},{"front":"Which of the following steps are part of the design phase in DLD?","options":{"A":"Test","B":"Validate","C":"Prototype","D":"Scope","E":"Ideate"},"back":["B","C","E"]},{"front":"What aggregations are defined by the sap.suite.ui.commons.ChartContainer?","back":"content, dimensionsSelector, customicons"},{"front":"Which elements of SAP Fiori can be assigned to business roles?","back":"Spaces, Business Catalog Groups, Business Catalogs"},{"front":"Which info will be used for creating a destination in SAP BTP for SAP Fiori elements development?","options":{"A":"Virtual name in SAP Cloud Connector","B":"Internal name in SAP Cloud Connector","C":"External name in SAP Cloud Connector","D":"Internal address of SAP Backend Server"},"back":["A"]},{"front":"What impact does SAP Fiori have on Business?","back":"Digitalization, Simplification, Leads to re-imagination of processes"},{"front":"Which applications can be used as entry point to create evaluations?","back":"Query Browser, View Browser"},{"front":"Which enumeration defines the various binding modes provided by SAP?","back":"sap.ui.model.BindingMode"},{"front":"Which areas are part of analytic list page","back":"Title Area, Visual Filters, Content Area"},{"front":"How can you enable adaptation at runtime for SAP Fiori Apps?","back":"Target Mapping to runtime authoring plugin, User role SAP_UI_FLEX_KEY_USER, SAP Fiori Catalog /UIF/SAP_RTA_PLUGIN"},{"front":"Which system environments offer the UI theme designer?","back":"SAP Enterprise Portal, SAP Netweaver Application Server ABAP, SAP Business Technology Platform"},{"front":"What is the nature of the overview page floorplan?","back":"You want to show all information that is needed by the user on a single page, based on a user specific domain or role."},{"front":"In which cases, is a local annotation better than a CDS annotation?","back":"Complex UI relevant annotations, You want to use annotations which are not supported by your current ABAP version"},{"front":"Which of the following features can be used to describe a module?","options":{"A":"Name","B":"Association","C":"Definition","D":"Scope","E":"Dependencies"},"back":["A","C","E"]},{"front":"To add a header facet, you should use @UI.HeaderFacet annotation and put it before the define statement of your CDS View","back":"False"},{"front":"For intent-based navigation, what does an intent consist of?","back":"Semantic Object, Action"},{"front":"What class in the SAPUI5 API supports back-end mock up and is recommended by SAP?","back":"sap.ui.core.util.MockServer"},{"front":"For what platforms is SAP Fiori Design Language defined?","back":"Web, Native Mobile, Conversational UX"},{"front":"Which of the following artefacts are contained in the OData URL structure?","options":{"A":"Service Root URI","B":"Header Data","C":"Resource Path","D":"Query Options"},"back":["A","C","D"]},{"front":"What is a SAP Fiori floorplan?","back":"A floorplan is a UI pattern that provides consistent UX"},{"front":"What ways are there of extending or modifying a SAPUI5 view?","back":"View Extension, View Replacement, View Modificaiton"},{"front":"Which of the following aspects are true for SAPUI5 UI element","options":{"A":"A UI element has an API","B":"A UI element does not have a renderer","C":"A UI element has a renderer","D":"A UI element can have events"},"back":["A","B","D"]},{"front":"What types of extensions/replacements are supported by SAPUI5","back":"View Replacement, View modification, Replace Service, Implement UI Controller hooks"},{"front":"What are the options for external navigation?","back":"Navigation to URL(As a Link), Navigation to intent(As a Link), Navigation to Intent(As a Button)"},{"front":"Which of the following components are part of the SAP Fiori Launchpad?","options":{"A":"Shell services","B":"UI2 Services","C":"Shell Container","D":"Runtime Container","E":"Runtime Configuration"},"back":["A","C","E"]},{"front":"Which of the following statements are correct with respect to the SAP Business Application Studio?","options":{"A":"BAS is a development environment for SAP ABAP","B":"BAS is a browser based development environment","C":"BAS provides application templates as a foundation of highly efficient app development","D":"BAS is based on an opensource IDE","E":"BAS provides WYSIWYG tooling"},"back":["B","C","D","E"]},{"front":"What are the differences between analytical entity set and normal entity set from an OData consumer perspective?","back":"Analytical Entity Set: Generates a new field for primary key, returns all data needed to analyze client, analyzes the use of the database and runs faster when SAP HANA is used as database compared to a normal entity set"},{"front":"Which aggregation is used to overwrite the standard behavior of a SmartField control?","back":"configure"},{"front":"What are catalog types in SAP Fiori?","back":"Replicable, Standard, Back-End"},{"front":"Which function must be called inside a control renderer to add the control ID to the DOM tree and support eventing?","back":"writeControlData"},{"front":"Which of the following model types are supported by SAPUI5","options":{"A":"XML","B":"JSON","C":"Odata","D":"SOAP"},"back":["A","B","C"]},{"front":"What are the limitations of publishing CDS as OData service by adding a @OData.publish:true","back":"Cannot Change names of entity sets, Only 1 level is taken into consideration when exposing associations, No customized ABAP code in SAP Gateway"},{"front":"Which terms are correct when talking about extensibility for SAP applications in a front-end server?","back":"SAPUI5 Adaptation/Extension, SAP Fiori Elements Adaptation"},{"front":"You want to define a property with the name width to enhance a standard UI5 control. The property should hold the current width of the UI control. What is the best approach to dfining the type of such a property?","back":"Define the property width of the type sap.ui.core.CSSSize"},{"front":"What is true of the SAP Business Technology Platform SAP Business Application Studio?","options":{"A":"It requires 0 installation","B":"Provides only SAP Cloud Programming Capabilities","C":"It is updated on a regular basis.","D":"Does only provide one workspace for project organization"},"back":["A","C"]},{"front":"What annotation is used to show fields of the projection list in the general information section?","back":"@UI.identification"},{"front":"What is needed to define target mapping for a Web Dynpro ABAP application?","back":"System Alias, Web Dynpro application, Web Dynpro configuration"},{"front":"Which element has the application as target?","back":"SAP Fiori app descriptor"},{"front":"What annotation is used to declare that a field of the projection list contains currency?","back":"@Semantics.currencyCode"},{"front":"What main aspects does the developer have to configure for a sap.viz.ui5.controls.VizFrame control?","back":"Dataset, DimensionsDefinition, MeasureDefinition, Feed"},{"front":"What are the main characteristics of a search field in SAP Fiori element-based applications?","back":"No value help dialog, Supports fuzzy search, Finda a keyword in multiply fields"},{"front":"What steps needs to be done in manifest.json if you need to hide variant function in a list report?","back":"Add setting to enable smart Variant Management, Set setting variantManagementHidden to True"},{"front":"Which of the following return types are supported by service operations?","options":{"A":"Complex Types","B":"Primitive Types","C":"Aggregation Types","D":"Infinitive Types"},"back":["A","B"]},{"front":"Which services are provided by the SAP HANA platform?","back":"Application Services, Integration Services, Processing Services, Database Services"},{"front":"Which of the following properties are relevant to the type of facet?","back":"purpose, type"},{"front":"When do you not use the overview page floorplan?","back":"A high-level or birds-eye view of an application content is sufficient. You want to show information about one object only, in this case use the object page instead. You just represent one application and less than three cards."},{"front":"Avaialbe options for creating a value help for a selection field","back":"By adding a foreign key annotation, By adding a value help annotation"},{"front":"What is the idea behind the golden rule of having one common UX?","back":"Having a common UX reduces training costs and increases the quality of data"},{"front":"Steps needed to create an association in CDS and expose it?","back":"Declare an association using 'association to' statement, Expose the association by writing its name in projection list"},{"front":"Which of the following are best practices when developing a SAPUI5 app?","options":{"A":"Descrbe your app using a set of metadata","B":"Use the Synchronous Model Definition Syntax","C":"Minimize the code in the index.html file","D":"Make use of patterns","E":"Use asynchronous model definition in your javascript code"},"back":["A","C","D","E"]},{"front":"In which base class implementation is the setModel function implemented?","back":"sap.ui.base.ManagedObject"},{"front":"Which of the following SAP Key UI technologies are currently recommended by SAP?","options":{"A":"Web Dynpro Java","B":"Web Dynpro ABAP with Screen Personas","C":"Classical Screen with Screen Personas","D":"Java Dynpro","E":"SAPUI5"},"back":["B","C","E"]},{"front":"Which of the following statements are true when talking about SAP Fiori?","options":{"A":"Is SAP UX that applies to modern user-centric design principles","B":"is SAP product for implementing SAP Enterprise Portal components","C":"is SAPs UI Technology for implementing applications for mobile devices","D":"can be personalized, is simple, and runs on any device","E":"Sap Fiori provides a consistent and role-specific experience accross all tasks, for all lines of business"},"back":["A","D","E"]},{"front":"What does a KPI consist of?","back":"Evaluation, Drill-down, Tile"},{"front":"What are the main spaces in the design thinking process?","back":"Problem Space, Solution Space"},{"front":"Which of the following information about an OData service should be provided as an annotation?","options":{"A":"The entities of an OData service","B":"Properties of an Entity Set/Collection","C":"The position for each field in a list report","D":"Data type for each property in an entity set/connection"},"back":["C"]},{"front":"How do you set a field as the title for a business entity?","back":"Add @UI.headerInfo.title.value for the CDS view and reference it to the field"},{"front":"The SAP Fiori Design Guidelines are available for various device types. For what device types are the design guidlines avialable?","back":"Sap Fiori for Android, SAP Fiori for Web, SAP Fiori for iOS"},{"front":"Which layers of settings are available for SAP Fiori?","back":"Personalization, Configuration, Customizing"},{"front":"Which class normally used as the base class when implementing a SAPUI5 view controller?","back":"sap.ui.core.mvc.Controller"},{"front":"What areas are mandatory in the tile layout?","back":"Header Area, Content Area"},{"front":"What is needed to define target mapping for an SAPUI5 application?","back":"Component ID, ICF Path"},{"front":"Which of the following describe benefits of SAP Fiori elements?","back":"Consistent UI Design, Less Support Effort"},{"front":"Which UI annotation is used in the object page to display the object header?","back":"UI.headerInfo"},{"front":"How can a renderer access the associated elements?","back":"SAPUI5 provides functions to access all properties, associations, and aggregations"},{"front":"Which of the following statements are true with respect to QUnit?","options":{"A":"Supports only synchronous testing out of the box","B":"QUnit is JavaScript unit and integration test framework","C":"Supports asynchrounous tests out-of-the-box","D":"Is capable of testing any generic JavaScript Code"},"back":["B","C","D"]},{"front":"What goals are chieved by a Lean Development Infrastructure?","back":"Allows for faster innovation through independently released and serial versions of components, Either automates or provides self-service response"},{"front":"What is the use of the annotation @UI.hidden?","back":"Prevent a column selected by user when customizing table settings."},{"front":"What are the goals of the SAPUI5 Framework?","back":"Provide a user interface technology for building and adapting client applicaitons, Provide an extensible framework for building desktop and mobile applications"},{"front":"From which control does the sap.m.App control inherit navigation capabilities?","back":"sap.m.NavContainer"},{"front":"sap.m.SplitAppMode where master is shown inside a popover when in portriat mode","back":"PopoverMode"},{"front":"When do you have to implement the SAP Fiori floorplan Initial page","back":"The initial page floorplan is used when the user needs to navigate to a single object."},{"front":"What attribute is assigned to the @UI.fieldGroup to add an identifier?","back":"qualifier"},{"front":"SAPUI5 provides two different router implementations. What router class is used in SAP Fiori apps as a router or as a router base class, when you want to implement your own router?","back":"sap.m.routing.Router"},{"front":"Which of the following statements are talking about the SAP Fiori app architecture?","options":{"A":"SAP Fiori apps are implemented using the component-based approach","B":"apps have an index.html file that is used for FLP integration","C":"apps need to have an app descriptor and describes the applications metadata","D":"apps should use the SAPUI5 core as a place to hold app data models"},"back":["A","C"]},{"front":"For a list report, which annotation is used to describe the name of business entity displayed on the report?","back":"@UI.headerInfo.typeNamePlural"},{"front":"Which different app types can be found in SAP Fiori?","back":"Conceptual, Technical"},{"front":"If your back end system is based on ABAP 7.50, which are available ways of using facets?","back":"Declare both field groups and facet as local annotation using BAS, Declare field group in CDS View declare facets as local annotation using BAS"},{"front":"Which shell configurations are available to adapt the header of the app?","back":"Embedded, standalone, headerless"},{"front":"Which personalization elements can be assigned to user roles?","back":"SAP Fiori Group, SAP Fiori catalog, SAP Fiori space"},{"front":"Which factors are key to the user experience with user assistence?","back":"Instant, Context-Sensitive, Seamless"},{"front":"How does the OData Model handle XRSF tokens?","back":"The OData Model fetches the token while reading the metadata and sends the token automatically in each write request header."},{"front":"The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to","back":"Create a Header Facet, Create a collection facet which is displayed as section, Create a reference under collection facet"},{"front":"Which UI Clients does SAP Screen Personas Support?","back":"SAP Business Client, SAP GUI for Windows, SAP GUI for HTML, SAP GUI for Java"},{"front":"Which types are supported as header facets for an object page?","back":"Field Group Facet, Plan Text Facet, Rating Indicator Facet"},{"front":"Which platforms support the integration of SAP Fiori?","back":"SAP Enterprise Portal, SAP Launchpad service, SAP Mobile Services"},{"front":"Which ABAP Transaction can be used to analyze the intents used in target mappings?","back":"/UI2/FLIA,/UI2/FLC,/UI2/FLPCA"},{"front":"Which of the following layouts, are described in version 1.48 of the Guidelines?","options":{"A":"Dynamic Page","B":"Full-Screen","C":"Split Screen","D":"Flexible Column Layout","E":"MobileDeviceLayout"},"back":["A","D"]},{"front":"What types of services are known or supported by the FLP","back":"Platform-specific services, Platform-independent services"},{"front":"Content Density factor: Reduces the dimensions of the controls, allowing more information to be displayed on the UI, ideal for devices operated by mouse and keyboard","back":"compact"},{"front":"Which of the following statements are true with regard to OPA5?","options":{"A":"Can be used for user interaction tests","B":"Can be used for SAPUI5 integration tests","C":"Is a view controller test framework","D":"Provides the possibility to test navigation"},"back":["A","B","D"]},{"front":"Which of the following make up the configuration of a tile for launcing a SAP Fiori app of type SAPUI5 in the FLPD","options":{"A":"Semantic object","B":"Launchpad creation via LPD_CUST","C":"Target Mapping","D":"Tile Configuration","E":"Tile implementation"},"back":["A","C","D"]},{"front":"Which native capabilities of a mobile device can only be leveraged when using SAP Fiori for iOS?","back":"Touch ID, Facetime, iBeacon"},{"front":"Which type of UI Control is used to embed a component into a component consumer?","back":"sap.ui.core.ComponentContainer"},{"front":"Which UI annotation is used to declare a field for the smart filter template?","back":"UI.selectionField"},{"front":"Which of the following statements are true with respect to fragments?","options":{"A":"Fragments are defined in a manner similar to views","B":"A fragment itself has a HTML representation","C":"Fragments are light-weight UI parts","D":"Fragments need a controller, similar to views."},"back":["A","C"]},{"front":"What message types are known to SAPUI5?","back":"Control Message, Server Message"},{"front":"What annotations are required to declare that an ABAP Core Data System Supports search capabilities?","back":"@Search.searchable"},{"front":"Which design pattern is used for resolving relationships between resources?","back":"Hypermedia design pattern"},{"front":"What can you do by editing manifest.json?","options":{"A":"Disable Object page","B":"Add object pages as sub page under an object page","C":"Define facets on Object Page","D":"Disable List Report"},"back":["A","B"]},{"front":"What to do implementing your own control renderer?","back":"You must implement a class that is derived from sap.ui.core.Renderer, the implementation should use the AMD syntax and it is also necessary to assign the renderer implementation to the renderer property of your UI control implementation."},{"front":"When should you not use the dynamic page layout?","back":"You are planning to use SAP fiori elements, such as the list report, analytical list page, overview page, or object page, which already incorporates the dynamic page layout. You want to implement an initial page or object page floor plan these floor plans already incorporate snapping header and footer toolbar features, the behavior is comparable to the dynamic page behavior, but the technical foundation is different. You only need to display a small amount of information, in this case use a dialog instead, if you cannot avoid using the dynamic page layout, use letterboxing to mitigate the issue."},{"front":"Which of the following are key features of SAPUI5?","options":{"A":"Full translation support","B":"Web Dynpro extensibility","C":"Responsive across browsers and devices","D":"Less open for custom development","E":"Based on open standards such as, JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5"},"back":["A","C","E"]},{"front":"When do you need to work with local data?","back":"When working with static data, to perform quick test without creating live entities on the back-end server"},{"front":"Which of followin description about search field is NOT true","options":{"A":"The search field is searching on more than one data field","B":"There is only one search field per list report","C":"The search field searches for only one data field","D":"Search field support fuzzy search"},"back":["C"]},{"front":"What steps aer used to display a field as a rating indicator?","back":"Set type of line item #AS_DATAPOINT, add a @UI.datapoint to the field and set visualization to #RATING"},{"front":"How can you activate an extension for the SAP Fiori Launchpad(FLP)?","back":"Target Mapping(/UI2/FLPD_CUST), Customer settings(/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF)"},{"front":"How is the extension type called to hide UI controls?","back":"View Modification"},{"front":"Which modes are provided by the sap.m.SplitAppMode enumeration?","back":"ShowHideMode, StretchCompressMode, PopoverMode"},{"front":"What of the following are important technologies of the ABAP programming model of SAP Fiori?","options":{"A":"SAPUI5 and SAP Fiori Elements","B":"IABAP Core Data Services","C":"BAdi and RFC","D":"SAP HANA"},"back":["A","B","D"]},{"front":"In what configuration area of the manifest.json file can you activate automatic message creation?","back":"sap.ui5"},{"front":"Why does it make sense to use the navigation API or SAPUI5 and concepts such as eventbus or the navcontainer functions of the base application?","back":"The API encures that the user of the app is able to store bookmarks for navigation targets, clearly seperates the navigation routes from application implementation"},{"front":"What are the main states of a file in GIT?","back":"Commited, Modified, Changed"},{"front":"When is the master-detail pattern not recommended?","back":"when you have to implement app wher user is able to apply complex filters on data in masterlist,or when user is able to display data in different facets such as charts and forms"},{"front":"How can you hide columns when the list report is accessed by a movile phone?","back":"Set UI.lineItem.importance for fields as #LOW or @Medium"},{"front":"Which mobile application type can be created using SAPUI5?","back":"Mobile Web App"},{"front":"What parameter must you provide when calling the simulate function of the mock server?","back":"The full qualified path to the local metadata file and the folder where the model data are stored locally."},{"front":"Which of the following can be used for usability assessment?","options":{"A":"Heuristic Evaluation","B":"User Testing","C":"User Observation","D":"Questionaires"},"back":["A","B","D"]},{"front":"What are the two aggregations provided by sap.m.SplitApp control to add page implementations?","back":"masterPages, detailPages"},{"front":"In which layers is metadata for SAP Fiori elements created?","back":"Core Data Services, User Interface"},{"front":"Which function invocation is necessary to setup routing inside a worklist app?","back":"this.getRouter().initialize()"},{"front":"Which dimensions define SAP Fiori?","back":"Concept, Design, Technology"},{"front":"What can be used as target in target mapping?","back":"Web Dynpro Application, Generic URL, ABAP Transaction, SAPUI5 Application"},{"front":"Which of the following SAP Fiori element based UIs are currently available?","options":{"A":"Wizard Form","B":"List Report","C":"Master-Detail","D":"Overview Pages","E":"Object Page"},"back":["B","D","E"]},{"front":"What is the base class for all UI controls in SAPUI5?","back":"sap.ui.core.Control"}]